Justin Le Tourneau

Address Phone Email Github

Columbia, MO 65201 (636) 697-2120 justin.letourn@gmail.com github.com/theWizardsBaker

Motivated Programmer and System Administrator with 8 years of experience designing, writing and deploying software for a variety of systems and use cases. Committed to improving user experiences through interface usability and functionality. Seeking a position that values learning, critical thinking and autonomy.

Skills

Programming:

- Proficient in various modern languages:
 - C++, Java, Javascript (ECMAScript), Python, Perl, PHP, Ruby, Shell Scripting
- Completed web projects using modern frameworks with loaders, bundlers and builders:
 - Web Front-End Vue.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Sass, Webpack build tools, etc.
 - Web Back-End Node.js, Express.js, Ruby on Rails, PHP, ColdFusion, Groovy, Django
 - o Web Services Socket.io, REST, SOAP, GraphQL, Sequelize, web tokens, etc.
- Completed mobile projects using Java in Android Studio, currently experimenting with Flutter
- Completed desktop projects using C++ in Microsoft WinForms and Qt
- Worked with search engines like Lucene and Elasticsearch
- Setup, optimize and designed schemas within different database implementations
 - \circ SQL Postgresql, SQLite
 - o NoSQL MongoDB, CouchDB, Neo4j
- Interface design and mockup with Mockflow and Adobe XD
- Git for version control and project organization

Administration:

- Install and manage CentOS, Redhat and Debian servers and virtual machines
- Manage web servers (Nginx, Apache, Tomcat, R Shiny, etc.)
- Add and upgrade hardware, install and compile software and manage storage
- Monitor performance. Manage system resources (example: cgroups)
- Relational (and non relational) database administration and optimization (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.)
- Scripting automated backups and other repetitive tasks
- Working with stakeholders to address needs for storage, setup, and provisioning. Implement standards for data storage and archiving.
- Teach researchers the terminal, the linux environment and how to use software like SLURM, Perl, Bash, etc.

Work History

Research Analyst - Linux Administrator, 2016 to Current **University Of Missou**

University Of Missouri – Columbia, Missouri

- Created a data portal, educational and other research websites for National Science Foundation project --Missouri EPSCoR Project
- Write and maintain bioinformatics research software for genome assembly browsers and genomic data mining
- Collaborate with faculty, postdocs and students to solve technical problems and contribute to research projects.

 Help with R state writing and running SUIRM jobs writing scripting / programming for pipelines and
 - Help with R stats, writing and running SLURM jobs, writing scripting / programming for pipelines and projects (C++, Shell, Javascript, Python, Ruby, etc.)
- Contributed software for research papers on genetic tools, bioinformatics and educational software
- $\bullet \quad \text{Maintain 10 high-performance research servers and their many kvm / vmware virtual machines (around 20)} \\$
- Install and manage software (WARF, R, Matlab, genetic pipelines, SMRTLink, etc.) for statewide project (EPSCoR) servers and research lab servers
- Install, configure and maintain backups and machine images

Quetza Software CTO, 2018 to Current

Quetza Software LLC – Columbia, Missouri

- Founded software company for developing agricultural educational products for academic and industry use
- Single full-stack developer for SeeGenetics and SeeBeefGenetics web applications. Created applications, authentication service, key / licensing software, educator portal. Designed both game and key features.
- Worked with co-founder (PhD in Genetics) to hone educational content

Programmer Analyst, 2012 to 2016

University Of Missouri – Columbia, Missouri

- Built custom web applications for financial officers and controllers
- Wrote software to interface with credit card companies and the campus bookstore
- Re-wrote old, custom, legacy software and re-tooled for modern use and maintenance
- Created custom framework for quickly building financial reports

Freelance Developer, 2006 to 2012

Self Employed – St. Louis, Missouri

- Wrote software and web applications for various clients in the St. Louis area, for example:
 - C. Rallo Meat Company
 - created software to link scales together for pricing information
 - created mobile apps for various in-store calculations and pricing
 - Saint Louis Wrestling Officials Association Scheduling website for Missouri high schools and officials

Education

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics And Computer Science, 2011 **Webster University** - Webster Groves, MO